virtualterminalnetwork.com 2014-02-09

# Privacy Policy - virtualterminalnetwork.com

 Our mission is to enable merchants and buyers in Nigeria to buy and pay for tangible products and services securely online. VTNetwork Limited is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent organization whose mission is to build user’s trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the site www.virtualterminalnetwork.com. Because this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to our users privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe.

If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, they should first contact   
Customer Service Department at VTNetwork Limited:   
Email: [ support@virtualterminalnetwork.com](mailto:support@virtualterminalnetwork.com)   
Mailing address: Suite S8 Febson Mall, Plot 2425, Herbert Macaulay Way, Wuse Zone 4, Abuja. 

If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should contact TRUSTe at [ http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint&url=www.virtualterminalnetwork.com](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint&url=www.virtualterminalnetwork.com)  
TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with us to resolve your concerns.

**Information Collection and Use**  
VTNetwork Limited is the sole owner of the information collected on virtualterminalnetwork.com. VTNetwork Limited collects information from our users at several different points on our Web site.

**Registration**  
In order to use this Web site, a user must first complete the registration form. During registration a user is required to enter contact information such as name and email address, business and home address. We use this information to contact the user about services on our site for which he has expressed interest. Users may also be required to provide demographic information such as income level and gender. For your security, all users are required to supply unique user id and password during registration in order to personalize account profile for each member. 

Send Money: When you send money to a non VTN member, we collect the email and mobile phone number of the recipient. This information is required in order to create a temporary account login for the recipient. The recipient will receive an email notification with the temporary account login details. On first logon, the recipient must update their account. There is no need to re-register at this stage.

Fund withdrawal: We collect your bank account information where the fund is deposited

Send SMS: In order to forward your SMS send request, we collect the mobile phone number of the recipient, first name, last name, and local government if available.

Purchase / Sell GSM Card and Gift Card: We collect the email and mobile number of the recipient of the GSM card and/or Gift card to fulfill your order.

Forums: When creating a forum account, we collect information such as your first name, last name, username, and home page web address. Additionally we keep and store your address book and member directory on our secure server. Users are able to edit this information at any time.

Helpdesk tickets: When creating tickets, we collect information such as your first name, last name, and username.

Career Opportunities: When you apply or submit job application to us online, we collect information such as your first name, last name, and curriculum vitae or resume.

Contact Importer: When you import contacts from your email program such as yahoo, Gmail, hotmail etc, we ask you to login using your login details. We do not store any of your login information supplied, however we do store the email of those invited and we do send out reminders to them on your behalf periodically. The information sent out is generic and forwarded to the email box of the recipient. Your email is mentioned as the person inviting them to try VTN. 

Merchant Account: Merchant account owners are allowed to add new employees to operate their account. We collect information such as first and last name of the employee, phone number, fax number, address, and age.

**Information Use**  
We use information collected to register you as a bonafide VTN member. Some of the information such as your email first name, last name will be made available to buyers and merchants dealing with you during any particular transaction.

**Profile**  
We store information that we collect through cookies, log files, clear gifs, to create a profile of our users. A profile stored information that we keep on individual users that details their viewing preferences. Consequently, collected information is tied to the users personally identifiable information to provide offers and improve the content of the site for the user. This profile is used to tailor a user’s visit to our Web site, and to direct pertinent marketing promotions to them. We will not share your profile with other third parties without your consent. Consent is sought at the time of registration or during occasional promotional offers to our members.

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s computer tied to specific information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. For the session ID cookie, once users log off, the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user’s hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions. 

By setting a cookie on our site, users do not have to log in a password more than once,   
thereby saving time while on our site. If users reject the cookie, they will not be able to use our site nor be able to participate in any of our services. Persistent cookies enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.

Some of our business partners use cookies on our site for example. However, we have no access to or control over these cookies. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by virtualterminalnetwork.com only and does not cover the use of cookies by any third parties. 

**Log Files**  
Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for   
aggregate use. IP addresses are tied to personally identifiable information to enable our Web-based service. 

**Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)**  
We employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. The main difference between the two is that clear gifs are invisible on the page and are much smaller, about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. Clear gifs are not tied to users’ personally identifiable information.

Clear Gifs can 'work with' existing cookies on a computer if they are both from the same Web site or advertising company. That means, for example, that if a person visited “www.virtualterminalnetwork.com”, which uses an advertising company’s clear gif, the Web site would match the clear gif`s identifier and the advertising company’s cookie   
ID number, to show the past online behavior for that computer. This collected information would then be saved in the database.

In addition, we use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by the recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns.

**Communications from the Site**  
We send all new members a welcoming email to verify password and username. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter, we ask for contact information such as name and email address. Out of respect for our users privacy we provide a way to opt-out of these communications by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the newsletter.

We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account we reply via email or phone, in accordance with the users wishes. On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email. Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. However, these communications are not promotional in nature. 

**Sharing**  
We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement. We do not share, sell, rent, or trade your personal information with third parties for their promotional purposes.

**Legal Disclaimer**  
Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site.

**Third Party Intermediaries/Service Providers**  
We use other third parties such as an email service provider to send out emails on our behalf. When the user signs up for these particular services, we share names or other contact information as necessary for the third party to provide that service. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes.

**Business Transitions**  
In the event virtualterminalnetwork.com goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, users’ personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. 

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications may opt-out of receiving these communications by replying to unsubscribe in the subject line in the email or email us at support@virtualterminalnetwork.com 

Users of our site are always notified when their information is being collected by any outside parties. We do this so our users can make an informed choice as to whether or not they should proceed with services that require an outside party.

**Links**  
This Web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, virtualterminalnetwork.com, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.

**Surveys**  
From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information such as name and shipping address, and demographic information such as zip code. Contact information will be used with the survey to notify the winners and award prizes. Anonymous Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. Users’ personally identifiable information is not shared with third parties unless we give prior notice and choice. Though we may use an intermediary to conduct these surveys or contests, they may not use users’ personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. 

**Tell-A-Friend**  
If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, we ask them for the friend’s name and email address. VTNetwork Limited will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site. VTNetwork Limited stores this information for the sole purpose of sending email and tracking the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact VTNetwork Limited at http://www.virtualterminalnetwork.com to request the removal of this information from our database.

**Import Contacts**  
We utilize an import contacts feature to help you keep in touch with your contacts and/or other members. We make it easy for you to invite people from your email address books to join you on our Site. At your request we will search your email address book to help you import your contacts to our site. You have control over who should receive the invitation. Once you submit the request, the invitation bearing your email is sent to the emails of those selected from your contact list. We also send reminders to your contact every 14 days to join VTN. The email invite that will be received by a contact will come to them from the VTN web site on your behalf and your email, first name and last name will be shown as the person inviting them to join VTN.

**Chat Rooms, Message Boards, and Public Forums**  
Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example in forums, on message boards, through e-mail, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. In short, by posting personal information online that is publicly accessible, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.

**Security**  
This Web site takes every precaution to protect our users’ information. When users submit sensitive information via the Web site, their information is protected both online and off-line.

When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information such as bank account numbers, that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when users are just ‘surfing’.

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users’ information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Our employees must use password-protected screen-savers when they leave their desk. When they return, they must re-enter their password to re-gain access to user information. Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. 

Every 6 months, as well as any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our users’ information is protected. Finally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are in a secure environment, behind a locked cage in a locked facility. 

If users have any questions about the security at our Web site, users can send an email to support@virtualterminalnetwork.com

**Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information**  
If a user’s personally identifiable information changes such as zip code, phone, email or postal address, or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or /deactivate users’ personally identifiable information. This can usually be done at the member profile page or by emailing our Customer Support at support@virtualterminalnetwork.com

**Notification of Changes**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

If, however, we are going to use users’ personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users via email.

**Contact Information**  
If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at:

 Corporate matters, please write to:   
VTNetwork Limited   
Suite S 8 Febson Mall, Plot 2425, Herbert Macaulay Way, Wuse Zone 4, Abuja, Nigeria  
Web site URL: http://www.virtualterminalnetwork.com  
Email: support@virtualterminalnetwork.com

Open an Account
